progress.com 2017-11-15

# Privacy Policy - Progress

Please note this governs the use of the Progress Software website. For the Privacy Policy governing the Telerik website please use the following [link](http://www.telerik.com/company/privacy-policy). 

**Last update: May 3, 2016**

We at Progress Software Corporation (“Progress Software” or “we”) are constantly striving to provide excellent service to you, our customers and business partners, while building a long-lasting relationship with you. To achieve these goals, we occasionally need information about you when you visit our sites.

This policy covers how Progress Software collects, uses and protects the information we gather through your use of the Progress Software products, Progress Software Websites (defined below) and in connection with off-line communications. Specifically, Progress Software may collect this information from electronic analytics, offline and online registrations and forms, communications and interactions, and sales inquiries and transactions. We also may use third party sources, such as opt-in lists. Please note that this policy may still apply if you elect private browsing.

No matter how Progress Software comes to have your information, we want you to know that we respect the privacy of your information and that you should be aware of how we handle it.

**Links to Other Sites**

This policy covers the information practices of our websites that link to this policy, which includes but is not limited to: [www.progress.com](http://www.progress.com/en/index.html) and https://[community.progress.com](https://community.progress.com/), as well as all international domains and subdomains (collectively referred to as “Progress Software Websites”).

Our Progress Software Websites contain links to other company websites. Please be aware that our privacy policy does not apply to these other websites. Although Progress Software uses great care to select content for our Progress Software Websites, including links to websites of third parties, we disclaim any responsibility for content that is found on these other websites. We encourage you to review the privacy statements of the other websites to understand their information practices. 

**Our Commitment to Your Privacy**

Progress Software does not:

  * Sell the names and addresses of our customers and/or site users to outside vendors.

Progress Software does:

  * Safeguard customers’ information from unauthorized access. 
  * Collect, maintain and use customer information as necessary to provide the most helpful and targeted products and services to meet customers’ needs (e.g. customer care or new products or services). 
  * Honor customers’ requests to remove their names from our telephone or mail solicitation lists in a timely manner. Just [Contact Us](mailto:unsubscribe@progress.com). 
  * Maintain confidentiality of customer information when undertaking projects with other companies.

Progress Software has always valued your privacy, and we reinforce this belief throughout our organization. Your information will be protected as described unless the specific Web page says otherwise. If you have further questions about our privacy policy, please [Contact Us](mailto:unsubscribe@progress.com).

**Information Gathered and Tracked by Progress Software**

**Product Usage Information Collected Through Telerik Analytics.**

In order to help Progress Software improve your experience with the Progress Software products and services, we use Telerik Analytics to monitor and identify trends and usage statistics. Telerik Analytics may collect certain information during a product download, product installation or update, while you are using certain Progress Software products and services. Such information may include, without limitation, how often different features are used, how often different buttons and menu items are clicked, execution time for different operations, error reports, download location, software version, platform information, application/product usage, features usage, exception tracking, OS information, and product logs. The information will be transmitted to and stored by Progress Software on its server, and/or by Progress Software’s service provider(s) on its servers. Progress Software does not use Telerik Analytics to collect any information which personally identifies you. The collection of this non-personally identifiable information will cease once your use of the Progress Software products or services has ceased. However, the information collected may be retained, accessed, and used by Progress Software as long as necessary for the purposes described herein. 

For more information on Telerik Analytics, please visit: <http://www.telerik.com/analytics>

**Organizational and Personal Information You Knowingly Give Us.**

Within our Progress Software Websites, you may be asked to give us personal or organizational information in order to purchase or receive information about a product or service. We may collect this information through different methods, including:

  * **Registration Forms.** We encourage all visitors to register with Progress Software, although registration is not required, except for access to our premium content areas. The registration forms require users to give us accurate contact information (like name and email address) and references that help us better serve you. Your name and email address may be used to send you information about our company, product updates, special offers, and newsletters. To opt out of receiving communications from Progress Software, please [Contact Us](mailto:unsubscribe@progress.com). 
  * **Order Forms and Enrollment Forms.** Our order forms securely collect visitor’s contact information and financial information (like your credit card number and other billing information). Contact information on the order form is used for order fulfillment and may be shared with our Partners or Resellers if that is necessary to fulfill your request. The information that we require in our order form is only used to process your order quickly and accurately. Your contact information will only be used to send you the product that you purchase and your billing information will only be used to bill you for that product. During the purchasing process, you may be given the opportunity to sign up for future e-mailings regarding our products, services, and promotions. If you sign up, we will share your contact information with other Progress Software partner companies only, not with other outside companies.

You may also be given the option of registering a profile with us which would store your name, purchase history, and billing information to make it easier for you to shop and purchase products/services from us in the future. You may opt out of this feature at any time by changing/canceling your profile online.

Progress Software may collect other information, including, but not necessarily limited to:

  * Contact information, such as name, physical address, telephone number(s), email address, and company. The majority of the information collected under this category is business contact information and when this information is collected in forms on our Progress Software Websites, it is collected and/or transmitted using Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology. 
  * Transactional information, including information about the products and services you purchase or download or about which you make an inquiry. 
  * User preferences, such as product requirements, areas of industry interest, newsletters, community choices and other information you select in the customer profile when registering on Progress Software Websites or indicated by your use of the Progress Software Websites. 
  * Financial/credit card and payment information. Please see the “How Progress Software Uses and Shares This Information” section for more information.
  * Event and conference participation information, such as lectures, classes or booths attended or visited during an event or conference hosted or attended by Progress Software. If we use electronic tracking technologies at an event, we will provide notice in the event registration materials and/or correspondence.
  * Other information which may include, but is not limited to, browser and device information, data collected through automated electronic interactions, application usage data, demographic information, geographic or geo-location information, statistical and aggregated information. Statistical or aggregated information does not directly identify a specific person, but it may be derived from personal information. For example, we may aggregate personal information to calculate the percentage of users in a particular zip code.

We may also supplement information you provide with information received from third parties.

**Information Gathered through Electronic Protocols.**

**Statistics and Information Collected as You Browse Progress Software Websites**

As you browse our Progress Software Websites, Progress Software’s Web servers collect information about your visit, not about you personally. Via Web server logs, we monitor statistics such as:

  * How many people visit our Progress Software Websites. 
  * Which pages people visit on our Progress Software Websites. 
  * From which domains our visitors come (e.g., “yahoo.com” or “aol.com”).
  * Which browsers people use to visit our Progress Software Websites.

While we gather this type of information, none of it is associated with you as an individual. We use these statistics to improve our Progress Software Websites, to monitor their performance, and to make it easier for you and other visitors to use the sites.

Our Progress Software Websites also log Host Names (or IP addresses when the Host Name is not available) for systems administration and security purposes. These logs are monitored and analyzed to maintain systems and information security and allow us to constantly improve the value and the availability of the Web content.

**Cookies**

A cookie is a small, encrypted data string our server writes to your hard drive that contains your unique User ID. Cookies on the Progress Software Websites may collect a unique identifier, user preferences and profile information and membership information. Progress Software’s server will query your browser to see if there are “cookies” previously set by the Progress Software Websites.

We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies to deliver Web content specific to your interests and to control access to restricted content. Session ID cookies expire when you close your browser. Persistent cookies remain on your hard drive after you leave our Progress Software Websites. The majority are set to expire within 90 – 365 days. We also use cookies to collect general usage and volume statistical information that does not include personally identifiable information. 

A cookie cannot be used to access or otherwise compromise the data on your hard drive. While we do not offer an opt-out for cookies, browsers provide you information and control over cookies. You can set your browser to alert you when a cookie is being used, and accept or reject the cookie. You can also set your browser to refuse all cookies or accept only cookies returned to the originating servers. You can generally disable the cookie feature on your browser without affecting your ability to use the site, except in some cases where cookies are used as an essential security feature necessary for transaction completion and might be required to complete certain functions on our Progress Software Websites.

**Flash Cookies**

We may use flash cookies, also known as “local shared objects”, on our Progress Software Websites that employ Flash technology. Flash cookies are small files similar to browser cookies and are used to remember the site’s settings to personalize the look and feel of the site. Like normal cookies, Flash cookies are represented as small files on your computer.

**Embedded URLs**

We also use a tracking technique that employs embedded URLs to allow use of the site without cookies. Embedded URLs allow limited information to follow you as you navigate the site, but is not associated with personal information and is not used beyond the session.

**Embedded Pixels**

On our Progress Software Websites, we may use embedded pixel technologies on selected pages for the purposes of identifying unique user visits to the Progress Software Websites as opposed to aggregate hits. In addition, embedded pixels or other technologies may be used in emails to provide information on when the email was opened to track marketing campaign responsiveness; information collected using these technologies may be associated with the recipient’s email address.

**Third Party Cookies**

Progress Software has engaged one or more third party service providers to track and analyze usage and volume statistical information from visitors to the Progress Software Websites, as well as to optimize and serve ads based on your past visits to our Progress Software Websites. The service provider(s) set cookies on behalf of Progress Software. One such service provider is Google Analytics. We use Display Advertising and Remarketing with Google Analytics. As a result of these cookies, third party vendors, including Google, will show our ads on sites across the Internet. You may opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising or customize Google Display Network ads by using the [Ads Preferences Manager](https://www.google.com/settings/u/0/ads?hl=en&sig=ACi0TCjy4Nf13pOV3osY_1OLnVqxGhEtwNJZEJjENJQTn7loHbzl_8rZw9ff12ft2XYL3hY9nFTQ0aIcNnDlxHcNS3K9E2MVgfbhD3oLE9xPHJvm9J2IxbMKCfhnok7QEiKwAP9b34jGXeFsT-iJoAE2tS9rUHSu_REDy76Apj6nbB-ESfl7p6Co15gDKC_MpryLZhOliUuL) on Google’s website.

**Widgets**

Our Progress Software Websites include Widgets, which are interactive mini-programs that run on our site to provide specific services from another company (e.g., links to bookmarked sites). Some information, such as your email address, may be collected through the Widget. Cookies may also be set by the Widget to enable it to function properly. Information collected by this Widget is governed by the privacy policy of the company that created it. 

**How Progress Software Uses and Shares This Information**

The information you submit on Progress Software Websites may be used or shared with third parties for any of the following purposes:

  * **To engage in transactions.** We may use personal information such as name, physical address, telephone number, email address, and company to engage in transactions with you, including contacting you about your order. 
  * **To process transactions.** We may use financial/credit card and payment information to process your order. Personally identifiable information that is needed in order to issue an invoice is stored on Progress Software Web servers in a commercially reasonable manner designed to safeguard against unauthorized access. We have put in place the appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. We do not store unnecessary information about you or for an unnecessary length of time. We may need to share some of this information with delivery services, credit card clearing houses and other third parties to complete the transaction. If we use an automated process to collect your credit card information, we may share this information with a third party vendor specifically selected for its superior practice, in which case we do not retain a copy of that information on our servers.
  * **To provide support or other services.** We may use your personal information to provide you support or other services you have ordered, as well as product updates, product patches and fixes and other similar communications. 
  * **To tailor marketing to your needs and respond to your requests.** We may use your personal information to notify you about new product releases and service developments, to respond directly to your requests for information, or pass your contact information to the appropriate Progress Software distributor or reseller for further follow-up related to your interests. 
  * **To provide online forums and social networks.** Some services available on the Progress Software Websites permit you to participate in interactive discussions, post comments, opportunities or other content to a bulletin board or exchange, or otherwise engage in networking activities. Some of these services are moderated; all may be accessed for technical reasons. Progress Software does not control the content that users post to these forums or social networks. Content posted in these public areas, including advice and opinions, represent the views and is the responsibility of those who post the content. Progress Software does not necessarily endorse, support, verify or agree with the content posted. Any personal information that you choose to submit in such a forum may be read, collected, or used by others who visit these forums, and may be used to send you unsolicited messages. You should carefully consider whether you wish to submit personal information to these forums or social networks and should tailor any content you submit appropriately and in accordance with the relevant terms of use. 
  * **To post testimonials.** We post testimonials on our Progress Software Websites which may contain personal information. Prior to posting the testimonial, we obtain the customer’s consent to post their name along with their testimonial. 
  * **To administer product downloads.** We may contact you if you download products to confirm certain information about your order (for example, that you did not experience problems in the download process), discuss the downloaded products or provide marketing or sales information about related products and services. We also may use this information to confirm compliance with licensing and other terms of use and may share it with your company. 
  * **To communicate with you about a conference or event.** We or our partners may communicate with you about a conference or event hosted or co-sponsored by Progress Software or one of our partners. This may include information about the event’s content, event logistics, payment, updates, and any additional meetings, special demonstrations or other customer facilitation that we may provide related to an event for which you have registered. We may contact you after the event about the event and related products and services and may share information about your attendance with your company. 
  * **To comply with legal requirements.** Progress Software may be required to disclose your personal information in order to comply with legally mandated reporting, disclosure or other legal process requirements. We will use reasonable efforts to limit the personal information it provides for these purposes.

**Information Security**

The security of your personal information is very important to Progress Software. We have in place physical, administrative and technical safeguards designed to protect your personal information from unauthorized access. In addition, Progress Software uses standard security protocols and mechanisms to exchange the transmission of sensitive data such as credit card details. When you enter sensitive information such as your credit card number on our site, we encrypt it using secure socket layer (SSL) technology.

In the event that your personal information is acquired, or is reasonably believed to have been acquired, by an unauthorized person and applicable law requires notification, we will notify you of the breach by email, fax, or U.S. mail. We will give you notice promptly, consistent with the reasonable needs of law enforcement and/or Progress Software to determine the scope of the breach and to investigate and restore the integrity of the data system.

**Service Providers**

We use third parties to assist you if you have questions while using our sites, teleconference services to provide you with webinars and demos, and a service provider to host and provide our content. When you sign up to receive any of these services, we will share your personal information only as necessary with the third party solely for the purpose of providing that service. In addition, we may use a specialized third party for our subscription billing platform.

We provide the information to our trusted distribution partners who work on behalf of or with Progress Software under confidentiality agreements. These companies may use your information to help Progress Software communicate with you about offers from Progress Software and our partners. These companies do not have any independent right to share this information. If you would like to opt out of having your information shared with these third parties you may [Contact Us](mailto:unsubscribe@progress.com), but please note that opting out may preclude you from licensing certain products due to our point of sale processes. 

**Commitment to Children’s Online Privacy**

Progress Software Websites are not directed at children. Progress Software does not knowingly accept online personal information from children under the age of 18. If you are under 18 or otherwise would be required to have parent or guardian consent to share information with Progress Software, you should not send any information about yourself to us. 

**Cross Border Transfers**

We are a corporation with operations worldwide, and have developed global data practices designed to assure your personal information is appropriately protected. Please note that your personal information may be transferred, accessed and stored globally as necessary for the uses stated above in accordance with this policy. By using the Progress Software Websites, you consent to the transfer of information to countries outside of your country of residence, which may have different data protection rules than those of your country.

### Sensitive Information

We ask that you not send us, and you not share any sensitive personal information (e.g., information related to racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religion or other beliefs, health, criminal background or trade union membership).

**Opt-out Policy and Procedure**

Our Progress Software Websites provide users with the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from us (and our partners) at the point where we request information about you. In addition, from within the www.progress.com subscription center (<http://businessmaking.progress.com/forms/SubscriptionMgt-English>), you can unsubscribe to the various communication offerings at any time, by deselecting the vehicles you do not wish to receive or by opting-out of all e-communications. Please note that opting-out of all communications will suppress every piece of electronic information from Progress Software and is not restricted to only the communications listed on the subscription center page. Additionally, anyone who wishes to remove their information from our database to not receive future communications or to no longer receive our service can [Contact Us](mailto:unsubscribe@progress.com).

Some non-marketing communications are not subject to general opt-out, such as communications related to product download, sales transactions, software updates and other support related information, patches and fixes, quality assurance surveys, conferences or events for which you have registered, and disclosures to comply with legal requirements, as well as communications with partners, including product alerts, updates, marketing and sales materials and other notices related to partner status.

**Correcting/Update Policy**

If you have any privacy concerns or would like to correct and/or update your information, please [Contact Us](mailto:unsubscribe@progress.com).

While the majority of questions and issues related to access can be handled quickly, complex requests may take more research and time. In such cases, issues will be addressed, or you will be contacted regarding the nature of the problem and appropriate next steps, within thirty days.

**Oversight**

If you have comments or questions about our privacy policy, please [Contact Us](mailto:unsubscribe@progress.com). We will address any issue to the best of our abilities.

**Changes to Policy**

Progress Software will occasionally update this privacy policy. When we do, we will post a prominent notice in this section of this policy notifying users when it is updated. If we are going to use your personal information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection, we will notify you via email, and you will have a choice as to whether or not we use your personal information in this different manner.

This privacy policy revises the privacy policies dated August 1, 2014 and **November 15, 2011**.
